<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">small data&#58;<br>big benefit</title>
<subtitle type="text">A short tagline</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2014-01-20T14:30:15-05:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Walter Bennette</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>bennette@iastate.edu</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Model based classifier improvement through the generation and selection of instance candidate subsets]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/articles/Model-based-classifier-improvement-through-the-generation-and-selection-of-instance-candidate-subsets" />
  <id>/articles/Model-based-classifier-improvement-through-the-generation-and-selection-of-instance-candidate-subsets</id>
  <published>2012-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2012-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Walter Bennette</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>bennette@iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;By: Walter Bennette, Dr. Sigurdur Olafsson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data preprocessing to improve the quality of data utilized by classification algorithms is an important step in knowledge discovery that can be performed in part by instance selection algorithms.  In this paper, concepts from column generation and the set covering problem are used to construct high quality subsets of training instances to be used as decision variables in such instance selection procedures.  A greedy and Nested Partitions selection procedure are used with the constructed decision variables and show that improvements of classifier accuracy are possible for a variety of datasets using decision tree, naïve Bayes, and logistic regression classifiers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/Model based classifier improvement through the generation and selection of instance candidate subsets.pdf&quot;&gt;Click here for the full article in PDF!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/Model-based-classifier-improvement-through-the-generation-and-selection-of-instance-candidate-subsets&quot;&gt;Model based classifier improvement through the generation and selection of instance candidate subsets&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Walter Bennette at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;small data&#58;<br>big benefit&lt;/a&gt; on August 10, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Instance selection for simplified decision trees through the geneneration and selection of instance candidate subsets]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/articles/Instance-selection-for-simplified-decision-trees-through-the-generation-and-selection-of-instance-candidate-subsets" />
  <id>/articles/Instance-selection-for-simplified-decision-trees-through-the-generation-and-selection-of-instance-candidate-subsets</id>
  <published>2011-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2011-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Walter Bennette</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>bennette@iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;By: Walter Bennette, Dr. Sigurdur Olafsson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decision trees are a useful tool to help in the extraction of information from 
databases, but all too often this ability is clouded by the complexity of the tree structure 
resulting from the decision tree algorithm. Methods such as tree pruning, attribute selection, 
and most recently, instance selection, currently exist to simplify the decision tree structure. 
We present an alternative instance selection procedure for simplifying decision trees that 
improves upon previous methods by increasing the quality of the space to be traversed for 
finding an acceptably simplified decision tree through the identification and grouping of 
important instances. Experimental results from this procedure are then presented and 
compared to decision trees with no prior simplification effort applied. We show that in some 
cases we are indeed able to identify important group of instances, and subsequently are able 
to generate a high quality solution space for finding simplified decision trees. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/Instance selection for simplified decision trees through the geneneration and selection of instance candidate subsets.pdf&quot;&gt;Click here for the full article in PDF!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/Instance-selection-for-simplified-decision-trees-through-the-generation-and-selection-of-instance-candidate-subsets&quot;&gt;Instance selection for simplified decision trees through the geneneration and selection of instance candidate subsets&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Walter Bennette at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;small data&#58;<br>big benefit&lt;/a&gt; on May 09, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>